Xavier Guihot

Data Engineer

1544 avenue Jules Grec, 06600, Antibes, FR

☑ https://xavierguihot.github.io ☑ x.guihot@gmail.com ☐ +33 # ## ## ## ##

XavierGuihot in XavierGuihot

Big Data Engineer with 3+ years of experience in interpreting and analyzing data for driving business solutions. I am highly proficient at building complex and efficient Scala/Spark data pipelines. While mainly focusing on data mining, I also enjoy displaying data in a meaningful way.

SKILLS

Data Mining
Master

Data Visualisation
Advanced
d3 | python

Full Stack Developer

-uvanceu

mongodb | django | javascript | tdd

Data Science

Advanced

clustering | hyperparam tuning | bi | ab testing | sampling

Travel Industry

spark | scala | etl | hadoop

Advanced

flight search engine

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer - Data engineer at Amadeus IT Group October 2014- Current

Sophia Antipolis, (FR) http://www.amadeus.com

Amadeus is a global distribution system providing search, pricing, booking, ticketing and other processing services in real-time to travel providers and travel agencies.

I am part of the data mining team in charge of the flight search engine analytics.

- Development of many Spark pipelines over billions of records on 30TB-RAM hadoop clusters
- Full stack development of Travel Intelligence visualisation webapps
- Customer choice modeling in order to improve and adapt which flight recommendations are returned, resulting in verified conversion improvements (up to 10%)
- Main role into transitioning workflows and pipelines into Amadeus new Hadoop production cluster (architecture, testing, resiliency, monitoring, git loading container principal reviewer)

Final year internship at Airbus Group April 2014- October 2014

♀ Toulouse Blagnac, (FR) http://www.airbus.com

Airbus is a multinational corporation that designs, manufactures, and sells civil and military aeronautical products worldwide. During my final year internship, as part of the simulation department, I've had the opportunity to develop a workflow editor tool.

■ First full-stack development experience, getting through each step of the application development cycle

Internship at Karlstad University July 2013- August 2013

TCP simulations with NS2 (network simulator) of large-scale experimental measurements on different cellular networks using different technologies (3G, 4G, TCP variants, ...).

EDUCATION

Engineering School at ISAE SUPAERO

2011 - 2014

♀ Toulouse, (FR)

Major courses: critical computer systems | intelligent systems | aeronautics | mechanical engineering | avionics | fluid mechanics

ISAE: Graduate Institute of Space and Aeronautical Engineering.

French equivalent of a Master's Degree in Engineering

University at Paris South 11

2009 - 2011 ♥ Orsay, (FR)

Major courses: maths | physics | computer science

Two-year university degree in mathematics and physics (DEUG).

Ranked 2 out of 307 in physics and 5 out of 307 in mathematics at the CCP DEUG entrance exam for engineering schools.

LANGUAGES

French English
Native speaker Fluent

INTERESTS

Sport Coding Travel

Skills acquired: swimming | cycling | sailing | skiing

Skills acquired: hackerrank | personal projects

Skills acquired: youtube